Guide to the Muawia Barazangi papers, 1969-2015..
Barazangi, Muawia papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Muawia Barazangi papers, 1969-2015.
16-14-4328
Muawia Barazangi
6 cubic feet.
Correspondence, reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection contains materials relating to Barazangi's career in seismology, including Cornell Program for the Study of Continents (COPSTOC) Syria project and Programme for Assessment and Mitigation of Earthquake Risk in the Arab Region (PAMERAR).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Muawia Barazangi was born and raised in Damascus, Syria. He graduated and obtained his BS degree in 1965 from Damascus University, majoring in physics and geology. Subsequently, he was granted a research assistantship from the University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, where he obtained a Master degree in applied geophysics in 1967. For his Ph.D. he moved to Lamont Doherty Earth Observatory at Columbia University in New York City, and obtained his Ph.D. degree in 1971 majoring in seismology. During his stay at Lamont he was involved and participated in numerous field projects, collecting seismological data, including the western USA and the southwest Pacific (Tonga, Fiji, and Vanuatu). When his Ph.D. advisor at Columbia, the late Professor Jack Oliver, moved to Cornell University in 1971, Muawia joined him as a research scientist and subsequently became a full professor. He taught in the Department of Earth and Atmospheric Sciences and served as the Associate Director of the Institute for the Study of the Continents (INSTOC). He also served in 1978-1980 as an associate professor and chairman of the Department of Geophysics at the Faculty of Earth Sciences, King Abdulaziz University, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia. In 2009 he retired and became a professor emeritus.
The focus of Barazangi's research at Cornell was on seismotectonics at regional and global scale, including seismicity of the earth, geometry and structure of subducted plates at converging plate boundaries, intraplate structure and tectonic activities, active continental collisions zones, historical earthquakes, paleoseismology and trenching of active faults, and evaluation and assessment of earthquake hazard. He also initiated and participated in the development of a comprehensive Geographic Information System (GIS) for the Middle East and North Africa (MENA). More information can be found at: http://atlas.geo.cornell.edu.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection contains materials relating to Barazangi's career in seismology and tectonics, including Cornell Program for the Study of Continents (COPSTOC) Syria project and Programme for Assessment and Mitigation of Earthquake Risk in the Arab Region (PAMERAR).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Barazangi, Muawia.
Subjects:
Seismology.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
The Guide to the Muawia Barazangi papers, 1969-2015, shows a considerable diversity of the scientific projects, activities, and publications that Muawia initiated and/or accomplished during the 50 years of professional career. It should be emphasized here that this available collection of documents is not complete, since many of past documents were lost over the years. However, this available collection is a true representation of Muawia professional career of about 50 years. The funding to support the different research projects was also considerably diversified, and mostly was based on writing proposals and competing for the research dollars. For example, grants were received from the National Science Foundation, Department of Defense, Department of Energy, United Nations, UNESCO, UNDP, Petroleum Research Fund and many large oil companies. Needless to say, the accomplished research was performed by numerous graduate students and research staff under the direct supervision and input from Muawia. The research results were published in over 130 research papers in numerous and diverse refereed scientific journals and edited monographs.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Morocco Project Documents
Series II. Syria Project Documents
Series III. Project Files
Series IV. Programme for Assessment and Mitigation of Earthquake Risk in the Arab Region (PAMERAR)
Series V. Lectures, Workshops, Conferences, and Seminars
Series VI. Miscellaneous documents
Series VII. Department Files
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Morocco Project Documents
  - Subseries Ia. Atlas Mountain Belt
    - Correspondence and research proposal submitted to Centre National de Coordination et de Planification de la Recherche Scientifique et Technique, 1986-01-1986-11 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and research proposal submitted to Centre National de Coordination et de Planification de la Recherche Scientifique et Technique, 1986-01-1986-08 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Includes agreement with Cornell.
    - Correspondence, 1986-09-1986-11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Memorandum and correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Atlas project documents and notes, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Research proposal submitted to Centre National de Coordination et de Planification de la Recherche Scientifique et Technique, 1986-11 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Project notes and documents, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and research proposal submitted to the United States Agency for International Development, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Kinemetrics proposal for the Atlas Seismic Network in Morocco, 1986-08-06 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Dr. Hatzfeld, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Correspondence, implementation plan
    - Support letters, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Seismotectonics paper materials, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Neotectonics paper materials, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Project quarterly reports, notes, and documents, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 15-17)
    - Final report and documents, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - NSF proposal, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 19-21)
  - Subseries Ib. General Project Documents
    - GEONA/Gvishiani, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Office National de Recherches et D'Exploitations Petrolieres (ONAREP), 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
    - IUGG, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Documents, proposals, and correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence with Morocco concerning gifts and microfilms, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Morocco trip, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Kinemetrics proposal for Seismic Networks in Morocco, 1985-07-26 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Morocco project documents, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Morocco trip, 1992-10 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Morocco trip, 1993-06-1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Ben Sari visit, 1995-03 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Demnati visit, 1995-03 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Demnati visit, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Morocco trip, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence and notes, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - GPS, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Networks paper, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Proposal material, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Cornell Morocco project, Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Series II. Syria Project Documents
  - Subseries IIa. Syria/Cornell Program for the Study of Continents (COPSTOC)
    - COCORP/COPSTOC material, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Syria/COPSTOC correspondence, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Syria/COPSTOC summary, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Notes, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Syrian visit, 1990-06 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Syria visit, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Syria summer, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Trip to Damascus, 1992-02 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Trip to Damascus, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Syrians visit, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Information for sending report and invitation letters, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Information for sending report and invitation letters, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Information for sending report and invitation letters, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Notes and documents, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Syria refraction data, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Consortium for Continental Reflection Profiling (COCORP) Syria, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Consortium for Continental Reflection Profiling (COCORP) Syria, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Notes and documents, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
    - Executive summary, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Executive summary, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Executive summary, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Executive summary, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Executive summary, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Project reports, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Report, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Annual Syria/COPSTOC project report, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Annual Syria/COPSTOC project report, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Annual Syria/COPSTOC project report, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Annual Syria/COPSTOC project report, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Conoco, 1997-2002 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Unocal, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Marathon, 1988-1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Sun, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - BHP, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - United Meridian Intr. Corp., 1997 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - British Gas, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Mobil, 1989-1998 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - AEC International, 1997-2001 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Apache Corporation, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Ocean Energy, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Oil Co. Committee, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - ARCO, 1988-2000 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Occidental OXY, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Art Green visit/Exxon, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Exxon, 1988-1998 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Amoco, 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - COPSTOC meeting, Houston, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Syria/COPSTOC project report presented to Unocal, 1994-03 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Syria/COPSTOC project report presented to ARCO, 1994-03 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Syria/COPSTOC project report presented to British Gas, Exploration and Production, 1993-02 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Syria/COPSTOC project report presented to Exxon, 1994-03 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Syria/COPSTOC invitations, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - COPSTOC, 1987-1992 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Subseries IIb. General project documents
    - Syria/UNESCO, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Syria/UNESCO proposal, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Offshore seismics, Syria, Lamont, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Syrian visit, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - SPC Syrian visit, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Kinemetrics, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Petroleum Research Fund/Syria, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Syria Network, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Syria Network visit, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Syria Network, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Memorandum of understanding for scientific and technical cooperation between Syria and Cornell, 1997-04 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Commission for the Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty Organization proposal, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Proposed east Syria meeting, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Syrian GPS project, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Correspondence and documents on Syrian projects, 1996-2004 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Kinemetrics, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - UNESCO/ICL contract, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - World Map of Active Faults, Trifinov, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - United Nations: Transfer of Knowledge Through Expatriate Nationals, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Tectonic Mapping and Geological Evolution of Syria: Implications for Hydrocarbon Exploration, proposal, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - GIS/GPS material, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Export of seismograph to Syria, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Site selection and field strength study for the Syrian National Seismic Network, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Syria NRR, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      Includes maps of different seismic zones in Syria
    - United Nations/EQhazard Transfer of Knowledge Through Expatriate Nationals, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Report to the Syrian Atomic Energy Commission on the Neotectonis-seismotectonics Characteristics of the Different Proposed Sites for the Planned Nuclear Research Reactor, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 36)
- Series III. Project Files
  - Subseries IIIa. Turkey
    - Landsat TM vs. NPA group, UNOCAL and ARCO, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Turkey proposal, original, NSF, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Subseries IIIb. Yemen
    - Yemen seismics, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Yemen seminar material, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Subseries IIIc. Oman
    - A Plan for a Seismological Network in the Sultanate of Oman, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Subseries IIId. Saudi Arabia
    - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - University of Petroleum and Minerals (UPM) observatory, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Seismic observatory, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - UPM EQ project, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - UPM project, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - UPM proposal, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - National Network proposal, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
    - National Center for Science and Technology, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence and observatory documents, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Grant proposal: Exploration of the Deep Continental Basement of the Arabian Shield in Saudi Arabia using Seismic Reflection Profiling, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Western Regional Seismological Network, 1986-01 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Subseries IIIe. Kuwait
    - Kuwait project materials, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Kuwait proposal, 1989-1995 (Box 3, Folder 41-42)
    - Ali Al-Shamlan, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Project material, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence and documents, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Kuwait trip, 1995-03 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Kuwait Field Report, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Kuwait observatory, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Documents, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Kuwait prize, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Conference, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Project material, 1989-1995 (Box 4, Folder 3-5)
    - Geology department, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Firyal, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Subseries IIIf. General Project files
    Includes research papers, reports, and grants
    - NSF proposal: a geophysical study of the northeastern Meditteranean, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - American Geophysical Union correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - Calibration of Selected IMS Stations in the Middle East to Improve Seismic Event Location, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Report, proposal
    - Active Deformation and Earthquake Hazard Assessment along the Arabian-African Plate Boundary: Integrating InSAR and GPS measurements proposal, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - CTBTO Calibration programme, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Regional GIS Databases in Support of CTBT Monitorin, final report, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Collection of Ground Truth Data in the Middle East, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Digital Database Development and Seismic Characterization and Calibration for the Middle East and North Africa, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Hade report to UNESCO, 1995-06 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Seber UNESCO mission, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Collaborative Research: Active Deformation of the Central and Northern Dead Sea Fault proposal and review, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency proposal, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Air Force proposal, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Imaging the Morphotectonic Setting of Seismic Events and their Propagation Paths: Methodology and Comparative Studies, 1988-1991 (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
    - Khaled Al-Maleh paper, 2000-07 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - NSF proposal: Collection and Dissementation of Geosience Data and Knowledge for the National Science Digital Library, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - NSF proposal: ITR/IM, A National Earth Science Knowledge Node for Research and Education, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - NSF proposal: The Third Digital Library for Earth System Education (DLESE) Annual Meeting, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - NSF proposal: Cooperative Research and Joint Workshop on the Tectonics of Eastern Turkey and the Northern Arabian Plate, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - NSF proposal: Collection and Distribution of Geosience Data and Knowledge for the National Science Digital Library, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - NSF proposal: Geospatial Data, Visualization, and Discovery in Support of a Digital Library for Earth Systems Education, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - NSF proposal: ITR/IM+EWF A Web-based Data Fusion, Interactive Mapping, and Information Delivery System, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Development and Validation of Travel Time Correction Grids for IMS Stations in North Africa and West Asia to Improve Seismic Event Location and Calibration proposal, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - A Prototype Information System for EarthScope proposal, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Middle East and North Africa Database Development and Research to Populate the Doe Knowledge Base, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Geoscience Knowledge System: Towards the Digital Earth proposal, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - DTRA final technical report, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Department of Defense DSWA/PRDA proposal, 1996-2001 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - UNESCO GIS Proposal, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Publications, 1969-2000 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      Includes Seismology, Iris, Bulletin D'Etudes Orientales, Monitor
    - GeoArabia, Volume 6 Number 4, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      Reprint, with article by Barazangi
    - World Seismicity Maps Compiled From Essa, Coast and Geodetic Survey, Epicenter Data, 1961-1967, 1969-02 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      Reprint, by Barazangi
    - Cornell Peace Studies Program: The Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty Issues and Answers, 1997-07 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - NSF western USA and a comparative study, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Original western USA, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - NSF materials, Detailed Mapping and Tomographic Study of Uppermost Mantle Pn Velocities in Western N. America and Other Continental Regions and Thickness of the Continental Lithosphere, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - NSF PANDA South America, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - NSF materials, A Comparative Study of the Seismotectonics of the Himalayan and Zagros Continental Collision Plate Boundaries, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 5-)
    - NSF project summary, Seismotectonics of the Himalayan and Zagros Arcs: Depth of Faulting and Spatial Extent of Deformation, and Uppermost Mantle Properties Beneath Tibet and the Western USA, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - IASPEI commission on geodynamics and tectonophysics, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Lebanese American University, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - IAEA/Haddad, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - DMA/DTED, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - IGCP/Arab Region, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - New Hebrides Project: A History, 1971-1974 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Anatom ANA station arrival times notebooks, 1977-08-1977-09 (Box 6, Folder 33)
- Series IV. Programme for Assessment and Mitigation of Earthquake Risk in the Arab Region (PAMERAR)
  - PAMERAR Syria, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 16-18)
    Correspondence, map, and documents
  - UNESCO Syria, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 19-21)
  - PAMERAR Syria, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
    Correspondence and documents
  - Syria proposal, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Yemen, 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Algeria, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - UNESCO Tunis, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Trip to Syria and Yemen, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Training seminar correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - PAMERAR monitoring Committee Meeting minutes, 1982-04 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Project draft plans, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - General documents, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Notes and correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Proposals, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - UNESCO Arab World Project, 1981-1984 (Box 3, Folder 35-36)
  - UNESCO project, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Final UNESCO report, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - UNESCO report, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Series V. Lectures, Workshops, Conferences, and Seminars
  - Seminar on Earthquake Hazards in the Eastern Mediterranean, Cairo, 1992-1993-10 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Arms Control and Regional Security Working Group, Helsinki, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - IDC training course, Vienna, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Iraqi Petroleum conference, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Global Geoscience Transects, Egypt, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Global Geoscience Transects, Kuwait, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Global Geoscience Transects, Morocco, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Global Geoscience Transects, Lebanon, 1987-1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Global Geoscience Transects, PAMERAR, Jordan, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Libya conferences, 1990-1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Iran, 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Iraq, 1988-1991 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Sudan, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Exploration in Yemen, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Syria, 1987-1992 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Global Geoscience Transects, 1985-12 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Global Geoscience Transects, Middle East and North Africa, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Global Geoscience Transects, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - High Precision Hyocenter Location and Seismic Tomography, Israel, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Earthquakes and seismotectonics of the Himalay/Tibet collision zone: a primer, 1991-11 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Includes transparencies
  - Oil vs. Middle East, 1990-1995 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Middle East course 108, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous lectures, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Commonwealth Club lecture, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Lecture invitation, ministry of Petroleum and Mineral Resources, 2007-03 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Oil and the World lecture, 2009-10 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Lectures, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - International workshop on active tectonic studies and earthquake hazard assessment in Syria and neighboring countries, 2009-11 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Syria workshop, 2004-09 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Lebanon conference, 1998-11 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Damascus University, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - International Symposium on Deep Structure of the Continental Crust: Results from Reflection Seismology, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    Letters from speakers
  - International Symposium on Deep Structure of the Continental Crust: Results from Reflection Seismology, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Announcements
  - International Symposium on Deep Structure of the Continental Crust: Results from Reflection Seismology, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    Post conference reports
  - International Symposium on Deep Structure of the Continental Crust: Results from Reflection Seismology, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Series VI. Miscellaneous documents
  - Articles and clippings, many of Barazangi, 1990-1999 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Cornell Chronicle CTBT article, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Mednet, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - M.N Qureshy correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Monitor/ARPA articles, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - General correspondence, 1991-2015 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Seismic station at Ithaca Paleontological Research Institute, 2004-2005 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Emeritus material, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Senior Scientist appointment material, 1981-1992 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - GSETT-3 Reviewed Event Bulletin map, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Documents from University of Damascus, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - EOS vol. 71, No. 39, 1990-09-18 (Box 6, Folder 35)